NEIL C ZIMMERMAN

585.281.1227 neil@abstractsec.com https://abstractsec.com

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Engineering lead focused on application development with specializations in information technology and cyber security, with an emphasis on the design and implementation of regulatory and security strategies and controls in the financial sector, while driving collaboration between technology and business teams.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Business Development Agile software development, Customer/IT relations management

Programming Languages Python, Java, JavaScript, PowerShell, BASH, SQL

Systems Integration Spark, Hadoop, Active Directory/LDAP, Nessus, Elasticsearch, Red Hat Linux

Other Experience SIEM design, Microservice architecture, RESTful web service design

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PALANTIR TECHNOLOGIES

PALO ALTO, CA + NEW YORK, NY

Business Development, Forward Deployed Engineer

Oct 2014 - Present

Technical lead on customer-facing projects, overseeing engineering teams focused on large-scale integration of financial and cyber data, and the development of analytical programs.

- Architected and led development of the next generation cyber analytics platform for use at institutional and government customers
- Managed the migration of legacy cyber risk analytics tooling to the company's common data back-end
- Led whiteboarding sessions with customer IT organizations deep-diving into data and analytics platform design, as well as storage and security architecture
- Managed the early-stage scoping and development of FX trader oversight and AML monitoring platforms at multiple systemically important financial institutions
- Developed data integration and entity resolution pipelines on top of Spark and Hadoop, unifying disparate off– the-shelf and custom-built systems, enabling customer analysts to perform investigations and modeling off of institutional data
- Implemented underwriting and actuarial data platforms for corporate liability (D&O), as well as property and casualty insurance lines

Technical Operations, Systems Engineer

Mar 2013 - Sep 2014

Application and infrastructure automation developer, integrating critical Microsoft and third-party platforms

- Integrated Active Directory with Human Resources platform, automating user provisioning and access management based on employment data
- Developed deprovisioning portal which tied into internal infrastructure, as well as cloud applications, allowing HR staff to track and self-service termination requests
- Developed various web applications and infrastructure APIs to solve novel problems brought forward by business teams throughout the organization
- Administered and deployed physical and cyber security systems infrastructure; such as DVRs, badging systems, password management and endpoint security services

ROCHESTER INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

Information and Tech Services, Systems Engineer (Part-time)

Dec 2008 - Feb 2013

ROCHESTER, NY

Systems administrator and developed

- · Worked on a team of engineers administering the enterprise Microsoft and VMWare infrastructure
- · Designed and implemented scripts for monitoring mission-critical infrastructure
- Implemented cross-platform secure access controls, applying defense-in-depth strategies to critical systems

CISCO SYSTEMS DALLAS, TX

CA Lab Operations, Co-op

Aug 2010 - Feb 2011

- Administered networking lab equipment and VMWare infrastructure used in recreating customer networks for troubleshooting
- Collaborated with full-time support engineers to troubleshoot customer networking issues

EDUCATION

ROCHESTER INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY [RIT]

ROCHESTER, NY

Information Security and Computer Forensics, B.S. (Honors)

2008 - 2013

Business Administration, Minor

Computer Science, Minor

ORGANIZATIONS

RIT: COLLEGIATE CYBER DEFENSE TEAM

Northeast Regional Champion, National Competitor

2012

RIT: SECURITY PRACTICE AND RESEARCH STUDENT ASSOCIATION

Member 2008 – 2013

Vice President of Programming 2010 – 2012